《星河战队3：掠夺者》
（联邦联播网）
（虫虫大战2）
（虫族新武器）
蝎子级脉冲战士
Scorpion-class pulse warriors.
神风轰炸甲虫
Kamikaze bombardiers.
战场上每天都有新虫族出现
Every day, new Bugs show up on the battlefield.
小心！趴下！
Watch out! Get down, get down!
多到让人不禁纳闷
So many that some wonder:
我们快打输了吗？
Are we losing this war?
一号GIQ
GIQ on one.
别打赌 各位
Don't bet on it, citizen.
在欧朋汉默测试场
Here at Oppenheimer Proving Grounds…
联邦科学家正在酝酿一些突袭…
…federal scientists are cooking up some nasty top-secret surprises…
…恶心的最高机密
…of their own.
想知道更多吗？
Would you like to know more?
但机动步兵团的最新武器
But the newest weapon in the Mobile Infantry's arsenal…
是一点都不机密的铲子
…is the not-so-secret shovel.
虫族火力更大就需要琐沟
Greater Bug firepower means trenches.
意即在罗库山挖琐沟
And that means digging here on Roku San…
这个曾经和平的农场星球
…this once peaceful farm planet…
已经变成二次虫战的新前线
…that has become the new frontline of the Second Bug War.
没错 士兵 用力挖吧
There you go, trooper. And put your back into it.
（反战者处死）
反对战争就是反对我们
If you're against the war, you're against us.
（叛徒）
一位联邦法官今天如是说
That's what a federal judge said today…
他宣布对于任何质疑 联邦道德的人来说
…when he declared that hanging is absolutely good enough…
绞刑算是客气的了
…for anyone who threatens the morale of the Federation.
全部处以死刑
And death. Execute them all.
（联邦法院法务部长奇瓦）
这是很简单的判决 做人讲话要小心
This is a very simple ruling. People need to watch what they say.
艾诺萝菲德上将 舰队情报局局长
Admiral Enolo Phid, division chief, Fleet Intelligence…
今天在地球司令总部 透露另一项隐忧
…voiced another concern from her headquarters at Terran Command.
如果宗教崇拜的复苏 在这里与外太空殖民地…
The revival of religious worship here and in the outer colonies…
…会造成煽动或任何方式的…
…will not be tolerated if it leads to sedition…
…动摇我们战争期间的努力 都是不被容许的
…or in any other way destabilizes our war effort.
想知道更多吗？
Would you like to know more?
他很黑 很英俊 是通灵战士
He's dark, he's handsome, he's psychic.
勇气 负责 荣誉
Courage, duty, honor.
如鹰一般翱翔天际
Eagle high above.
他是欧马艾诺克将军 人见人爱的空军指挥官
He's General Omar Anoke, the sky marshal everyone loves.
给我们力量 蠃得这场战争
And gives us strength To go and win this war.
在昨晚的战争集会上
And at last night's war rally…
他震撼了全联邦的听众
…he thrilled audiences all across the Federation…
激昂演出他最新畅销曲 《慷慨赴义就在今天》
…with a pounding rendition of his latest hit, "A Good Day to Die."
我们为正义而战
We fight for what is right.
崇高的牺牲
A noble sacrifice.
时候到了就义无反顾
When duty calls, you pay the price.
我愿为联邦奉献生命
For the Federation I will give my life.
慷慨赴义就在今天
It's a good day to die.
当你知道为何而战
When you know the reasons why.
我们就要为正义而战
Citizens we foght for what is right.
你们现在可以歌颂 空军指挥官艾诺克
And hey, citizen, now you can celebrate Sky Marshal Anoke…
同时支援我们的武力
…and support our war effort at the same time.
因为每天都是购物的好日子
Because it's always a good day to buy.
- 我愿奉献生命 - 勇气 负责 荣誉
- I will give my life - Courage, duty, honor.
我愿为联邦奉献生命
For the Federation I will give my life.
想买更多吗？
Would you like to buy more?
（军援司令部 罗库山）
敌袭！
Incoming!
- 退开！- 快跑！
- Clear out! - Run!
动作快！
Move, move, move!
你能走吗 大兵？
Can you walk, soldier?
- 可以 长官 - 很好
- Yes, sir. - Good.
帮个忙 捡起那只手臂 查出是谁的手
Give us a hand. Pick up that arm and find out who it belongs to.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
动作快 我们要在 两小时内完工
Mop up, people. We got brass up our ass in T-minus-2.
今晚要抽查吗 长官？
Surprise inspection, sir? Tonight?
空军指挥官随时会来查验
The SM can drop in and count the sheets any time he wants.
空军指挥官要来？
The sky marshal's coming here?
麦尼恩少尉 你敢叫他签名 我就开枪射你
Ask him for an autograph, Lieutenant Manion, and I will have you shot.
当然不会 长官
No, sir. Of course not, sir.
- 长官到 - 继续工作
- Officer on deck. - Carry on.
报告状态
Status?
- 亚契又在测试围蜥 - 笨虫
- Archie's testing the fence again, sir. - Stupid Bugs.
是讨厌不是笨 少尉
Pesky, not stupid, lieutenant.
继续加油 亚契 我早上要烤虫族
Keep it up, Archie. I like my Bugs fried in the morning.
舰艇下来了 上校
Boat coming down, colonel.
皮绷紧了 士兵们
Look sharp, troopers.
长官 空军指挥官是联邦最高机密
Sir, the sky marshal is the Federation's top-secret top secret.
你怎么知道他要来？
So how'd you know he was coming?
艾诺克的参谋长 以前是帮我擦鞋的
Anoke's chief of staff used to polish my brass.
你认识豪泽将军？
You know General Hauzer?
狄克斯豪泽也曾经是 像你一样的笨少尉
Dix Hauzer was a dope lieutenant just like you once upon a time.
两年就当将军 真厉害
Made general in two years. Some dope.
我花八年才当到上校
Only took me eight years to make colonel.
长官到
Officer on deck.
- 强尼瑞哥 - 你好 狄克斯
- John Rico. - Good to see you, Dix.
- 你好吗？- 很好
- How's it going? - Good.
我要介绍你认识一个人 我想我恋爱了
I have to introduce you to someone. I think I'm in love.
是吗？谁啊？
Yeah? Who'd have you?
他来了 动作快
Here he comes, everybody. Let's go, come on.
长官到
Officer on deck.
抱歉无预警的跑来 上校
Sorry to drop in unannounced, colonel.
但我有感觉 你预料到我会来
And yet I sense you expect my visit.
拍仔细了 中士 强尼瑞哥 P星球的英雄
Get in tight on this, sergeant. Johnny Rico, our hero of Planet P.
我只是尽本份
I just did my part, sir.
不 英雄激发勇气与牺牲
Oh, no. Heroes inspire courage, sacrifice.
- 牺牲？- 是的
- Sacrifice? - Yes.
要我们做得更好
By asking us to be better than what we are.
告诉我罗库山的情况 上校
Tell me about Roku San, colonel.
这些农夫会打仗吗？
Will these farmers fight?
他们需要我们 但不喜欢我们
They need us, but they don't like us, sir.
心比脑袋更善变
Hearts are more fickle than minds.
强尼瑞哥
Johnny Rico.
萝拉贝克？
Lola Beck?
你怎么在这里？
What are you doing here?
我是空军指挥官的驾驶
I fly the SM.
他要最好的
He gets the best.
你了解我的 强尼
Well, you know me, Johnny.
对 我了解你
Yes, I know you.
贝克舰长就是 稍早我提到的人
Captain Beck is the person I was talking about earlier.
你？
You?
跟萝拉？
And Lola?
有什么好笑的？
What's the joke?
贝克舰长 你该告诉我
Captain Beck, you should have informed me…
你跟瑞哥上校的关系
…of your relationship with Colonel Rico.
你知道我是公私分明的 将军
You know what I do out of uniform is off the clock, general.
你们三位显然 有很多事要讨论
You three obviously have much to discuss.
请他们喝一杯 上校 算我的
Buy them both a drink on me, colonel.
好的
Yes, sir.
- 你是麦尼恩少尉？- 是的
- Lieutenant Manion, isn't it? - Yes, sir.
- 不介意带我巡视吧？- 我？
- Care to give me the post tour? - Me?
您的歌我都有
I have all your songs, sir.
- 去吧 少尉 - 好的 长官
- Carry on, lieutenant. - Yes, sir.
请跟我来
Follow me, sir.
走吧 长官都下令了
Come on, kids. We got orders.
你们是我认识 最大个儿的女孩了
You boys are the biggest girls I've ever known.
你想它们是什么？
What do you think of them?
虫子？我讨厌它们
Bugs? I hate them, sir.
没人喜欢他们不了解的东西
Well, no one likes what they can't understand.
但是往想像力去看
But just look at the imagination.
它们的创意十足
The sheer virtuosity of their creation.
抱歉打扰您 可以请您在我头盔签名吗？
I hate to bother you, sir, but could you please sign my helmet?
当然可以 士兵
Of course, trooper.
- 谢谢长官 - 不客气
- Thank you, sir. - Anytime, son.
我只知道
All I know is…
它们今天的数量多了很多
…there sure are a lot more of them at the wire today, sir.
多了很多
A lot more.
也许它们听说了我要唱歌
Well, maybe they heard I was going to sing.
- 长官到 - 注意
- Officer on deck. - Look sharp.
稍息
At ease.
你们好
Gentlemen.
我把你跟某个 不是农夫的人搞混了
You got me confused with someone who isn't a farmer.
- 怎样能弄到那种帽子？- 加入军队尽一份力量
- How do I get me a hat like that? - Join up, do your part.
农夫嘛
Farmers.
- 我要问你一件事 - 抱歉 队长
- I'd like to ask you something. - Sorry, chief.
我已婚了
Already married.
我请他们喝一杯 拿瓶酒给我们
Buy them a drink on me, will you? And bring us a bottle.
安份点 哈朗
Hose your cage, Harlan.
这种人会害我们 输掉这场战争的
These are the kind of people who will lose this war for us.
为什么外太空殖民地的人 都不想作战？
Why is it no one in the outer colonies wants to fight?
罗库山曾是个好地方
Roku San used to be a nice place.
现在成了战场 他们怪到我们头上
Now it's war, and they blame us.
亚契今晚发飚了
Archie's cooking tonight.
- 是啊 - 没错
- Oh, yeah. - Yeah.
- 它们在想什么？- 亚契不会思考
- What are they thinking? - Archie don't think.
今天是烤虫的好日子
It's a good day to fry.
- 立正 - 稍息 士兵
- Ten-hut. - At ease, troopers.
太棒了
Fascinating.
它们今晚似乎很兴奋
They seem so excited tonight.
你真该听听它们的声音 它们在外头哀号呢
You ought to hear them, sir. They're howling out there.
放出来 士兵
Well, put them on the line, soldier.
什么意思 长官？
What does it mean, sir?
意思是我们受到测试 少尉
It means we're being tested, lieutenant.
测试我们的忠诚 智慧
Our loyalty, our intelligence…
还有想像力
…our imagination.
不好意思 长官 我弟弟真的很崇拜你
Excuse me, sir. My brother really loves you.
- 当然 他叫什么名字？- 凯文
- Of course. What's his name? - Kevin.
- 相信他会是很棒的新兵 - 谢谢你
- I'm sure he'll make a fine recruit. - Thank you.
- 可以麻烦你吗？- 当然没问题
- May I, sir? - Of course you can, trooper.
麦尼恩上尉 你敢请他签名 我就开枪射你
Ask him for an autograph, Lieutenant Manion, and I will have you shot.
他去哪儿了？
Hey, where'd he go?
敬我们
To us.
敬强尼 P星球的英雄
To John, hero of Planet P.
萝拉 两艘船被你击落
Lola, two ships shot out from under you.
我是做办公桌的
I fly a goddamn desk.
我打的是数字战 我做的就是这个
The battles I fight are with numbers. That's what I do.
我会的就是这个
That's what I know.
所以我知道
And that's why I know…
如果这里的人不站出来 我们就会沉船
…that if everyone in here doesn't step up, we're sunk.
- 敬联邦 - 敬联邦
- To the Federation. - The Federation.
“敬联邦”
"To the Federation."
狄克斯
So, Dix.
瑞哥和我结识时
Rico and I met…
强尼是大战英雄 我才六年级
…when Johnny was a big war hero and I was still a six.
毕业旅行 八天十个星球
Bond tour. Ten planets, eight days.
还记得乌龟湾吗？
Do you remember Turtle Bay?
狄克斯 你怎么认识约翰的？
So, Dix, how do you know Johnny?
他以前在地球司令部是我上司
Well, he used to be my boss at TCOM.
标准职位调动 我生命中最糟的一年
Standard rotation. Worst year of my life.
狄克斯每天都在 帮我收烂摊子
Dix saved my ass every day.
处决时间到了
Hey, it's hanging time.
上诉让人精疲力尽 他们都已和家人道别
Appeals are exhausted. Their families have said goodbye.
剩下的就是伏法
All that remains is payment for their crimes against you, citizen.
资深绞刑执行官慢慢来
The senior executive executioner is taking his time.
也许是在给讯息
Sending a message, perhaps.
要我们大家今晚深思
One for all of us to contemplate this evening.
我们的想法不论多讨人喜欢
That our ideas, no matter how pleasing…
都是危险的
…are dangerous.
都会产生行动与后果
That there are actions and consequences.
谁都不重要
That no one really counts very much…
除非我们顾全大局
…unless we are part of something bigger.
那就是正义
There it is, justice.
你们会付出代价的 上帝做我的见证
You'll pay. As God is my witness, you'll pay.
- 退后 - 等等
- Back off. - Hold on, hold on, wait, wait.
闪开 联邦的家伙
Hey, fuck off, feddy.
你们没搞懂 这是很清楚的教训
You guys fail to understand a very clear lesson here.
你要教训我吗？
You got something to learn me?
- 狄克斯 我们走吧 - 瑞哥上校 请你放尊重
- Come on, Dix, let's get out of here. - Colonel Rico, if you please.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
叫军警 我要逮捕他们 这是命令
MPs, now. I want them arrested. Everyone. That's an order.
遵命 长官 中士
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
你听到将军的话了
You heard the general.
朋友 你没大过联邦政府
My friends, you're not bigger than the Federation.
讲话小心一点 叫你做什么就照做
Watch what you say and do what you're told.
- 不然你要吊死我们吗？- 这由你决定
- Or you'll have us hung, is that it? - It's up to you.
狄克斯 我们带萝拉走吧
Come on, Dix. Let's get Lola out of here.
我不是你属下了 强尼 退下
I don't work for you anymore, John. Stand down.
你们听到没有？退下 这是命令
Did you hear that, everybody? Stand down. That's an order.
从现在开始 我自己处理
From now on, I take my own lumps.
让我来
I got this.
现在你违反了第五条款
Now you're in violation of Article 5.
第八条款
Article 8.
- 够了吗？- 退下 瑞哥
- Had enough? - Stand down, Rico.
退下
Stand down.
第十一条款
That's Article 11.
十一条款
That's 11.
让你成为…
Which makes you subject to…
- …特别命令86的对象 - 小心！
- Special Order 86. - Look out!
瑞哥上校 你违反命令
Colonel Rico, you're out of order.
请见谅 将军
Begging the general's pardon, sir.
我只是想阻止老朋友犯错
I was trying to keep an old friend from making an ass of himself.
友谊比不上职责重要 上校
Friendship means nothing next to duty, colonel.
而你忘了你的职责
And you have forgotten yours.
我们是来杀虫的 长官
I thought we were here to kill Bugs, sir.
不是杀农夫
Not farmers.
依煽动罪逮捕农夫
Arrest the farmers. Sedition.
- 还有瑞哥上校 - 好了 给我站起来
- And Colonel Rico too. - All right, on your feet, asshole.
- 罪名是不服从长官 - 狄克斯 住手
- Failure to obey a superior officer. - Hey, Dix, stop it.
强尼说的对
Johnny's right.
快走！
Move it!
贝克舰长
Captain Beck.
回到你的船上
Return to your boat.
中士 你听到命令了
Sergeant, you have your orders.
上校 请跟我来
Colonel, please come with me.
电子系统故障
Electrical system malfunction.
不会吧
Oh, no.
杀了它们 它们越过围墙了
Here they come, they're on the wall.
- 瑞哥 - 全部故障了
- Rico. - It's all down. Everything.
栅栏出故障了
The fence is down, sir.
- 栅栏呢？- 怎么会这样？
- The fence? - How could that have happened?
妈的 它们来了
Fuck, here they come.
可恶
Oh, shit.
我们需要增援
We need reinforcements.
现在就需要援兵 长官！
We need reinforcements now, sir!
- 我马上去 - 等等 你被捕了
- I'm on my way. - Hold on. You are under arrest.
- 这是你的遗言吗？- 不 这是命令
- Is that your final word? - No, that's an order.
我们军事法庭上见
I'll see you at my court-martial.
- 见到你真好 萝拉 - 是啊
- Nice seeing you, Lola. - Yeah.
让路 我们要出去
Make a hole, coming through.
小心 上校
Heads up, colonel.
继续走
Keep it moving. Keep it moving.
拜托 你们想活下去吗？
Come on, you apes. You wanna live forever?
动作快
Move it. Come on.
继续走
Keep it moving.
撤退
Fall back.
就防守位置 敌人来袭
Defensive positions. Incoming.
我们走
Let's go.
快 快
Go. Go.
没子弹 我没子弹了
Out of ammo, man. Out of ammo.
不！
No!
- 虫子！- 前后列队！
- Bugs! - Two lines! Front and back!
开火！
Fire!
枪榴弹！
Grenades!
发射！
Fire!
前进！
Forward!
瑞哥上校
Colonel Rico, sir.
- 报告状况 少尉 - 完全搞砸了 长官
- Situation, lieutenant. - Totally ominously fucked up, sir.
我把空军指挥官也跟丢了
And I lost the sky marshal too, sir.
很好 我们会一起被处死
Good. We'll all hang together.
你们知道怎么做 进去杀光它们！
You know what to do. Get in there and kill them all!
- 前进指挥部在哪？- 虫子
- Where's forward command? - It's Bugs.
是虫子 到处都是虫子
It's Bugs. Bugs everywhere you go, sir.
长官 你怎么在这儿？
Sir, what are you doing here?
你受伤了？我们得立刻送你上登陆艇
Are you wounded? We have to get you to the lander right now.
我没事
I'm fine.
大兵 快过来 我们得送空军指挥官到安全地方
Marines, gather around. We must get the sky marshal to safety right now.
遵命 列队 这边走 将军
Yes, sir. Formation. This way, general.
亚契
Archie.
危机解除
Clear.
继续走
Keep moving.
亚契 把锁打开
Archie. Get that paddock open.
我是豪泽将军 开门
This is General Hauzer. Open this door.
开门
Open the door.
长官
Sir.
把门关上！
Get this door closed!
威斯医生 这边
Dr. Wiggs, over here. Dr. Wiggs, we need you.
送他进去
Get him inside.
- 医务兵看着雷中士 - 知道了 长官
- Corpsman, see to Sergeant Rye. - Yes, sir.
该死的虫子 我恨它们！
Fucking Bugs. I hate them!
威斯医生 前面
Dr. Wiggs. Front and center.
- 他怎么了？- 小心点
- What's wrong with him? - Careful.
他受到惊吓 你没事吧 长官？
He's in shock. Are you all right, sir?
你没事吧 长官？
Are you all right, sir?
长官？
Sir?
- 我没事 - 太好了
- I will be. - Oh, good.
来吧 小心点
Here we go. Careful.
贝克舰长 我们几时离开？
Captain Beck, when do we leave?
不如就现在吧 长官？
How about T-minus-now, sir?
长官 我请求准许 留在罗库山
Sir, requesting permission to remain on Roku San, sir.
- 想当英雄吗 狄克斯？- 总得有人留下战斗
- Trying to be a hero, Dix? - Somebody's gotta stay and fight.
长官
Sir.
现在由瑞哥上校指挥
Colonel Rico is in command.
我被迫释放瑞哥上校
I was forced to relieve Colonel Rico.
他原本因为 不服从上司遭到逮捕
He's under arrest for acts of insubordination.
这是重罪 我为你朋友感到遗憾
Serious charges. I'm sorry for your friend.
也许你的命运 真的就在这里 狄克斯
Perhaps your destiny does lay here after all, Dix.
你去吧
Go find it.
祝你好运
And good luck, soldier.
等等
Wait.
你再考虑一下
Just think about this for a second.
你这是在为我们两个做决定
Because you're making a decision for the both of us right now.
我知道
I know.
狄克斯 我爱你
Dix, I love you.
我爱你
I love you.
开船离开吧
Blast off, Fleet.
各单位注意
Attention, all units.
我是豪泽将军
This is General Hauzer.
现在开始由我指挥
I am assuming command effective immediately.
进地堡！
Go to the bunker!
重覆 现在由我指挥 各单位指挥官请回报
Repeat, I'm assuming command. All unit commanders report.
立刻报告位置与状态
I want location and status. Now.
G琐沟失守了 长官
We lost G Trench, sir.
通知豪泽将军 好吗 少尉？
Put that in a memo to General Hauzer, will you, lieutenant?
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
我是豪泽 各单位注意 我再说一遍 现在由我指挥
This is Hauzer to all units. I say again, I'm assuming command.
它们在撤退 长官
They're pulling back, sir.
- 趴下！- 准备迎击！
- Get down! - Hit the deck!
准备行动
Clear the deck.
史基纳 海陶 守住那个洞
Skinner, Hightower, cover that hole.
准备迎击！
Prepare for attack!
轰炸甲虫！
Bombardier!
蝎子！是蝎子！
Scorp! It's a scorp!
蝎子
Scorpion.
蝎子！妈的！是蝎子！
Scorpion! Oh, fuck! Scorpion!
开火！
Fire, fire, fire!
榴弹枪！
Grenades!
我们回家吧 贝克队长
Take us home, Captain Beck.
五秒后进入曲速
Warp in five, number one.
遵命 豪泽将军怎么办？
Yes, ma'am. What about General Hauzer, ma'am?
他想战斗 听我倒数出发
He wants combat. Take us out on my mark.
五 四 三 二 一
Five, four, three, two, one.
然后他说 “那我们都能去睡了”
The guy says, "Man, then we can all get some sleep."
该死的亚契 真不敢相信我被咬了
Fucking Archie. Can't believe I got bitten.
没错 你被咬了
Yeah, he got you.
长官到
Officer on deck.
稍息
At ease.
做的好 中士
Nice work out there, sergeant.
谢谢长官 空军指挥官没事吧？
Thank you, ma'am. SM all okay?
多亏有你们
Thanks to you boys.
我们怎么说 大兵？
What do we say, marines?
- 没错 - 继续做事吧
- Yeah. - Carry on.
天哪
Oh, boy.
布里托队长 一切井然有序吗？
Chief Brittles, are we shipshape?
你会第一个知道的 舰长
You'd be the first to know, captain.
只是打声招呼 布尔
Just saying hi, Bull.
抱歉 长官
Excuse me, ma'am.
如果那是空军指挥官的晚餐 那你先走吧 荷莉
If that's the SM's dinner, after you, Holly.
谢谢长官
Thank you, ma'am.
你煮了什么 金格？
What's cooking, Jingo?
还不是老样子嘛
You know, the same old shit on a shingle.
- 喝酒吗 舰长？- 我在值勤 医生
- Drink, captain? - On duty, doc.
我也是
Me too.
贝克舰长 听我说一下好吗？
Captain Beck. Give a listen, will you?
今天我们在罗库山 遭遇沉痛的失败
Today we have suffered grave defeat at Roku San.
但我相信宇宙中 存在着平衡
But I am confident that there exists balance in the cosmos and…
打扰了 长官
Excuse me, sir.
我相信宇宙中存在着平衡
I am certain that there exists balance in the cosmos.
既然失败过 我们就会胜利
And where there is defeat, we will make victory.
你认为呢？
What do you think?
我明天要向国会演说
I have to address the council tomorrow.
长官 大家都爱胜利
Well, sir, everybody loves victory.
恕我失陪 我要回驾驶舱了
If you'll excuse me, I'll be getting back to the cockpit.
没有你 他们就处理不来吗？
Look, look, can't they manage without you just for once?
留下来谈谈吧
Let's stay and talk.
好的 长官 我很乐意
Certainly, sir, I'd be happy to.
抓稳了
Hold on.
我们从曲速摔出来了
We're falling out of warp.
长官 为了保护您
Sir, for your own protection…
我必须送您上登陆艇
…I'm gonna need to get you to the marine lander.
荷莉 跟着我们
Holly, stay with us.
- 什么撞上我们？- 我想我们刚才互撞了
- What just hit us? - I think we just hit each other.
来吧 荷莉 我们走
Come on, Holly, let's move.
- 士兵 向援救甲板报到 - 了解 贝克舰长
- Marines, report to the rescue deck. - I read you, Captain Beck.
我们马上过去
And we are on our way.
我们走
Let's go.
（高度警戒）
来吧
Come on.
大兵 在这里
Marines. Right here, brothers.
我们走
Let's go.
是反应炉爆炸吗 队长？
Was that a reactor, chief?
是二级爆炸 一级会把我们变成阳光
Secondary. Number one will turn us into daylight.
我没事
I'm okay. I'm okay.
- 弃船 队长 - 遵命 长官
- Abandon ship, chief. - Yes, ma'am.
雷中士 空军指挥官跟你走
Sergeant Rye, the SM goes with you.
知道了 长官 请跟我们来 长官
Yes, ma'am. Come with us now, sir.
贝克舰长 我希望你留在我身边
Captain Beck, I would prefer that you stay at my side.
好的 长官 队长 带其它人去坐逃生舱
Yes, sir. Crew chief, get everyone else to the rescue pod.
没问题
You got it.
- 厨房有点问题 - 金格 拜托
- We got a little problem in the galley. - Jingo, jeez.
笨蛋
Dumb ass.
- 你没事吧？- 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
去接空军指挥官
Go get the SM, Chick.
长官 这边请
Sir, this way.
不！可恶！
No! Damn it!
- 大兵 去坐你们的登陆舱 - 我们地面上见
- Marines, get to your lander. - I will see you on the ground.
各位 我们走 去坐逃生舱
Okay, people, let's move. To the rescue pod, now.
- 我们要坠毁了吗？- 没有 我们要去坐逃生舱
- Are we crashing? - No, we're getting into the rescue pod.
（罗库山败仗）
罗库山战线 是联邦防卫的关键
The Roku San line, key to the Federation's defense…
昨晚吃了败仗
…knows defeat in one night.
死了多少人？没人敢说
How many dead? No man can say.
但专家都同意一件事
Experts agree on one thing only:
责任明显落在 强尼瑞哥上校身上
Blame falls squarely on Colonel John Rico.
（瑞哥 P星球英雄蒙羞）
曾被誉为P星球的英雄
Once heralded as the hero of Planet P.
如今却蒙羞等待受审
Now disgraced and awaiting court-martial…
暂时囚禁在 阿拉莫湾联邦监狱
…from his cell at the Alamo Bay Federal Detention Facility.
在外太空殖民地 还有一场和平集会
Another day, another peace rally in the outer colonies.
联邦政府占尽好处
The Federation has taken advantage.
但这次不一样 因为他是艾莫戈尼夫
But this time it's different, because of Elmo Goniff.
我是公民
Hey, I'm a citizen.
授勋老兵变成和平主义者
Decorated veteran turned pacifist…
现在也成了日渐 壮的 公民联盟的领袖
…and now the leader of a growing coalition of citizens…
他们质疑联邦政府
…who question the Federation's administration…
造成虫族冲突
…of the Arachnid conflict.
为什么？我在信仰找到了答案
And counting. Why? I found my answers in faith.
我的信仰是对上帝 不是人
And I have faith in God, not people.
不计代价求和平 是人类的权利
Peace at any price is a human right.
还有其它的代价
And there are other costs too.
罗库山败仗 燃起反战运动…
Defeat at Roku San has fueled the anti-war movement…
…造成144名 外太空殖民地的学生…
…resulting in the deaths of 144 outer-colony students…
…与虔诚的反战份子丧命
…and religious protesters.
想知道更多吗？
Would you like to know more?
现在带您到 地球司令部的现场
We break net now to take you live to Terran Command…
空军指挥官欧·艾诺克 将向联邦人民演说
…where Sky Marshal Omar Anoke will address the Federation…
交待罗库山的危机
…on the Roku San crisis.
同胞们 今天我带着 沉痛的心来到这里
My fellow citizens, I come to you today with a heavy heart.
在过去12小时内…
Within the past 12 hours…
…我们在罗库山 遭遇屈辱败仗…
…we have suffered ignominious defeat at Roku San.
…不服从最高指挥…
Incompetence at the highest levels of command…
…遭到背叛…
…and betrayal…
…那些抗议 质疑…
…by those who would protest, question…
…犯下和平抗争的人
…and commit acts of civil disobedience.
我向你们保证 要为罗库山大败负责的人…
I assure you that those responsible for the catastrophe at Roku San…
…所有反对联邦政府的罪行 不论轻重大小…
…and all crimes against the Federation, large and small…
…都将受到惩罚
…will be punished.
我们的战争是人类的宿命…
Ours is a war of human destiny…
…结局只会有一个 那就是完全的胜利
…that will end only in total victory.
演说完毕
And we're out.
结束了 很好
Okay, let's wrap it up. Good.
怎么样？
So?
怎么了 将军？你看来不是很满意
What's the matter, general? You don't look very happy with me.
我们都明白 必须稳定民心
We all understand the need to maintain stability…
直到我们找到空军指挥官
…until we locate the sky marshal.
我很讶异见到你
I'm surprised to see you.
我以为你要花点时间 才能走出伤痛
I thought you'd take some time to recover from your ordeal.
空军指挥官会希望我 坐镇办公室的 上将
The sky marshal would want me in the office, admiral.
那当然
Naturally.
（地球司令部）
打扰一下 长官
Excuse me, sir.
抱歉 长官
Sorry, sir.
- 少尉？- 我姓兰柏
- Lieutenant? - Lamb.
（密件）
我知道不该提起这件事
I know no one's supposed to talk about it…
但空军指挥官的事我很遗憾 长官
…but I'm sorry about the sky marshal, sir.
那是机密 少尉 菲德会让你受绞刑的
That's classified, lieutenant. Phid will have your head in a noose.
但还是谢了
But thanks.
还有事吗？
Something else?
虫族隔离区昨天传来 求救讯号
A distress call came out of the AQZ yesterday.
为什么你会知道 而我却不知情？
And how are you aware of this and I'm not?
它是在我值班时传来的
The transmission came through on my watch, sir.
（方位座标保密）
席拉麦克号呼叫救援舰 听到请回答
Sierra Mike Uniform to Fleet Rescue. Come in, Fleet.
席拉麦克号 这里是救援舰
Sierra Mike Uniform, this is Fleet Rescue, over.
请求优先接回 空军指挥官外加五名船员
Requesting priority pickup for sky marshal plus five.
你上报之后结果呢？
What happened when you kicked it upstairs?
上级指示不予理会 包括之后的讯息在内
We were instructed to ignore it, sir, and all future transmissions.
我也不该说出来的
And I'm supposed to keep my mouth shut.
那你为什么过来 少尉？
That why you're here, lieutenant?
他们在外孤立无援 没有人想办法营救
They're out there all alone and no one's doing anything about it.
长官
Sir.
你从没来过 少尉
You were never here, lieutenant.
是的 长官 从来没有
No, sir. Never.
（艾诺萝菲德上将下令）
席拉麦克号呼叫救援舰 听到请回答
Sierra Mike Uniform to Fleet Rescue. Come in, Fleet.
席拉麦克号呼叫救援舰
Sierra Mike Uniform to Fleet Rescue.
听到请回答
Fleet Rescue, come in.
他们会来接我们吧 舰长？
They're gonna come and get us, right, captain?
他们要多久才会到？
I mean, like, how long till they get here?
给你 医生
Here you go, doc.
重覆一遍 席拉麦克号呼叫救援舰
I say again, Sierra Mike Uniform to Fleet Rescue.
听到请回答
Come in, Fleet.
有人在吗？
Is anyone out there?
我想联系不上了 金格 快出来
I don't think we're getting through. Jingo, get out of there.
为什么？我喜欢这里 好嘛
Why? I like it in here. Okay.
（太阳能电池耗尽 请充电）
太阳能电池需要充电
The solar cells need recharging.
没空在海边待上一天
Don't have time for a day at the beach.
虫子！
Bugs!
一个还是一千个？
One or 1000?
谁敢说那里没军队？
Who's to say there's not an army out there?
- 天哪 - 我什么都没看到
- Oh, God. - I didn't see anything.
可能是侦察队
Probably a scout.
我们必须立刻离开这片海滩
We need to get off this beach pronto, people.
留下逃生舱？
Leave the rescue pod?
那些虫子出现时 你想退到大海里？
You want your back to the water when these Bugs show up?
请便 医生
Be my guest, doc.
我们在天上的父 愿世人皆颂圣名
Our father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name.
愿您的国降临 愿您的旨意…
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done…
省省吧
Give it a break.
轻松点 舰长
Easy now, captain.
你什么都不确定 把我们都吓死了
You ain't sure, and you're scaring us all to death.
行在地上如同行在天上一样
On Earth as it is in heaven.
我们日用的饮食 今日赐给我们
Give us this day our daily bread and del…
你真的快把我逼疯了
You are really getting on my nerves.
你没理由那样做
You've got no cause to do that.
把手拿开 队长
Get your hand off me, crew chief.
你弄痛他了
You're hurting him.
人人都有思考的权利
Everyone's got a right to think what they want.
当然 只要他们放在心里就行
Sure, as long as they keep it to themselves.
拿装备 我们要走了
Saddle up. We're moving out.
等等 救援舰来找我们
Wait a second. When Fleet Rescue comes looking for us…
他们会先到这里吧？
…this is the first place they're gonna come, right?
我想是的 布尔
I expect they would, Bull.
那我们应该留在这里
Then we should stay right here.
如果虫族来袭 我们就躲到逃生舱里
And if the Bugs do attack, we just fall right back to the pod.
真聪明 布尔
Smart thinking, Bull.
你没遇过虫群吧 大个子？
You ever been in a swarm, big man?
虫群？天哪 不要
Swarm? Oh, my God, no.
它们会把逃生舱 当纸袋一样撕开
They'll tear this pod apart like a paper bag.
神哪 救救我们
Oh, God, save us.
准备好我们要走了 这是命令
Now, gear up, we're moving out. And that's an order.
我们在天上的父 愿世人皆颂圣名
Our father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name…
- 上帝会说话吗 - 你错了 贝克舰长
- Can the God talk. - You're wrong, Captain Beck.
上帝无所不在
God is everywhere, surrounding us.
你说什么？
Excuse me, sir?
我们都在用自己的方法 寻找上帝
All of us search for God in our own way…
不管我们有没有自觉
…whether we know it or not.
您真的相信吗 长官？
Do you really believe that, sir?
是的 荷莉
Yes, Holly, I do.
我不知道您也是信徒
I had no idea that you were one of us.
好 你们都可以去找上帝
All right. Well, all of you guys can go look for God.
我要去登陆舱那里
I'm heading for the Fleet marine lander.
他们有武器 说不定还有能用的通讯器
They've got weapons, maybe even a com that works.
而且只有一百公里远
And it's only about a hundred klicks away.
只有一百公里远
Only a hundred klicks away.
我们的存粮撑不了那么远
We ain't got rations for that.
你是胖子 不需要吃 出发了 各位
You're fat. You won't need any. Let's move, people.
强尼瑞哥上校 因为不服从命令
Colonel John Rico, for incompetence of command…
（阿拉莫湾联邦监狱）
攻击长官 蓄意疏忽
assault on a superior officer, and willful negligence…
导致数名士兵 在你的指挥下丧命
resulting in the deaths of several soldiers under your…command…
你被判以绞刑处死
you are sentenced to hang by the neck until you are dead.
（立刻生效）
行刑前你有什么话要说吗？
Do you have anything to say before the sentence is carried out?
动作快 好吗？
Get on with it, will you?
我们地狱见吧
I'll see you in hell.
怎么回事？
What the hell is this?
你今天走运
Your lucky day.
情报局 这是机密
Intelligence. Classified.
你敢说出去 下次就轮你上绞刑台
You talk, and next time it's your neck in the noose.
走吧 英雄
Let's go, hero.
你想亲手吊死我吗 狄克斯？
You gonna hang me yourself, Dix?
也许我有更好的事让你做
Maybe I got some better things for you to do.
你常来这里吧 狄克斯？
You come here a lot, don't you, Dix?
没想到你对政治犯有兴趣
Didn't know you were interested in political prisoners.
不是我的意思 我是跟空军指挥官来的
Not me. I come with the sky marshal.
- 来审问的 - 艾诺克喜欢接触人群啊？
- Interrogations. - Anoke likes the personal touch, eh?
不是你想的那样 不是人类囚犯
Not like you think. Not human prisoners.
你在P星球抓到的 第一个首脑就关在这儿
That first Brain, the one you captured on P, we keep it here.
- 它还活着？- 还长大了呢
- It's still alive? - Alive and a lot bigger.
没人知道它们能活多久
No one really knows how long they live.
有什么用处？
What's it good for?
艾诺克深深为它着迷
Anoke was fascinated by that thing.
我的命为何突然值钱了？
Why's my neck suddenly worth more than a piece of rope?
事关联邦的未来 强尼
It's about the future of the Federation, Johnny.
- 还有萝拉 - 那跟我有什么关系？
- And Lola. - What's that got to do with me?
- 我只信得过你 - 为什么？
- You're the only one I can trust. - Why's that, buddy?
因为大家都认为你死了
Because everyone thinks you're dead.
（确认7只）
（继续扫描）
（确认16只）
- 舰长？- 我看到了 金格
- Captain? - I see them, Jingo.
我数到16只
I count 16.
虫子？在哪里？
Bugs? Where?
- 不会吧 - 它们为什么停下来？
- Oh, no. - Why did they stop?
我们快走
Let's move.
- 布尔 - 干嘛？
- Bull. - What?
- 你跟我殿后 - 没问题
- You with me. - You got it.
它们在赶集我们
They're herding us.
为什么？它们可以轻易干掉我们
Why? They could have us easy.
也许我们受到 上天的眷顾
Perhaps we find ourselves under the grace of a higher power.
您真的这么想吗 长官？
You really think so, sir?
我心知肚明 荷莉
I know it in my heart, Holly.
您真的认为 我们受到上天保护？
Do you really think we're protected by some higher power?
唱歌没关系
Singing can't hurt.
提振士气还能杀时间 你不认为吗？
Lifts the spirit and helps pass the time, don't you think?
我认为我们没死 但我们早该挂了
I think we're not dead and we should be.
是啊
Yeah.
它巨大致命
It's big. It's deadly.
（Q弹争论）
人人都对新的Q弹有意见
And everyone's got an opinion about the new Q-bomb.
政客与民众担心传言
Politicians and citizens alike worry about the morality of a bomb…
这种炸弹威力大到 能炸毁星球
…rumored to be so powerful it can crack a planet.
发明一种武器 能够摧毁…
Creation of a weapon that can destroy the very planet…
…我佇立的这个星球 对全人类来说…
…on which I now stand is nothing if not a dangerous precedent…
…都是一个危险的先例
…for the entire human race.
人们不懂的是…
What people fail to grasp…
…宇宙间有好多星球
…is how many planets there are in the universe.
宇宙本身就经常 摧毁其它星球
And that the universe itself often destroys other planets.
联邦政府不能决定 一个星球的生与死
The Federation can't decide which planet lives and which planet dies.
上天的赐与 只有上天能收回
The Lord giveth and the Lord taketh away.
虫族如果有Q弹 你以为它们就不会用吗？
You think those dirty Bugs wouldn't use a Q-bomb if they had one?
但我们不是应该 更优于虫族吗？
But aren't we supposed to be better than the Bugs?
那是你说的 妈 这就是Q弹的争论
You said it, Mom. That's controversy with a Q.
想知道更多吗？
Would you like to know more?
（加入舰队 尽一份力）
（今天就加入！）
昨天我载士兵前往战区
Yesterday I dropped troopers into a combat zone.
今天我要飞往外太空殖民地
Today I'm flying to the outer colonies.
我是舰队的一员
I'm Fleet.
- 我也是舰队的一员 - 我们都是舰队的一员
- I'm Fleet too. - We're Fleet too.
我们需要飞行员 我们需要你
We need pilots. We need you.
我？真的吗？
Me? Really?
如果你数学能力强 反射指数高
If you have strong math skills, high reflex index…
HED高于8点1 我们现在就需要你
…and an HED of 8.1 or better, we need you now.
十六岁？没问题
Sixteen? No problem.
今天就开始 为你的未来受训
Start training today for your future, citizen.
人家说男生HED不佳 但我例外
People say boys don't give good HED. But I do.
加入舰队 你的未来无可限量
When you go Fleet, there's no telling where you'll end up.
我年轻的时候
You know, when I was young…
梦想着有一天 我会驾驶星舰
…I dreamed that one day I'd fly a starship…
甚至是拜访圣域
…or even visit Sanctuary.
舰队带我登上高峰
Fleet has taken me to the top.
加入舰队 能飞多高由你决定
How high you fly is up to you when you go Fleet.
何不今天就加入我们？
So why not do your part and sign up today?
我们驾驶舱见
See you in the cockpit.
想知道更多吗？
Would you like to know more?
（圣域 联邦舰队之家）
（方位保密）
强尼
Well, John.
你初次来到圣域
Your first time at Sanctuary.
- 真是惊人 - 没错
- So this is the big wow. - This is it.
要是虫族发现这里 它们就会击溃舰队
If the Bugs find this place, they'll knock out the Fleet.
还有外太空殖民地 机动步兵团守不住的
No Fleet, you lose the outer colonies. Mobile Infantry couldn't hold them.
然后是邻近一带
There goes the neighborhood.
- 下一站就是地球 - 没错
- Next stop, Earth. - Yeah.
所以圣域是战争的最大秘密
Guess that makes Sanctuary the biggest secret of the war.
就连空军指挥官都不知道
Not even the sky marshal knows where it is.
只有几个值得信任的 现役飞行员知道
Only a handful of active-duty pilots are entrusted with that information.
别告诉我
Don't tell me.
萝拉是其中之一
Lola's one of them.
对 如果找不到她 我们就完了
Yup, and if we don't find her, we're sunk.
（星舰示罗 雅典娜级）
（掠夺者计划）
我要派你去虫族隔黎区
I'm sending you to the Arachnid Quarantine Zone…
你准备好就出发
…as soon as you saddle up.
我们对这个星球 了解多少？
What do we know about this planet?
OM一号？一无所知
OM-1? Nothing.
连确切位置都不知道
We don't even have its exact position.
求救讯号呢？没有信号吗？
What about the rescue call? Wasn't there a beacon?
艾诺萝菲德不想救艾诺克
Enolo Phid doesn't want Anoke rescued.
- 我不懂 - 菲德想当艾诺克
- I don't get it. - Phid wants to be Anoke.
很高兴我只需要 打虫子就行了
I'm glad all I do is fight Bugs.
我会弄到座标让你去
So I'm gonna get the coordinates and you go in.
了解
Roger that.
但你凭什么这么肯定 他们还活着？
But what makes you so sure they're still alive?
萝拉很难死
Well, Lola's hard to kill.
如果这是秘密任务
If this mission is off the books…
你要怎么给我军团 入侵虫族隔离区？
…how are you gonna get me a regiment to invade the AQZ?
军团？差的远了
A regiment? Not even close.
- 那我有几个大兵？- 七个
- So how many troopers do I get? - Seven.
- 什么？- 包括你在内
- What? - That's including you.
你只派个步枪队 跟我去虫族的家？
You're sending me into the Bug house with a rifle squad?
何不干脆让他们 吊死我算了 狄克斯？
Why didn't you just let them hang me, Dix?
也许我是该那么做
Maybe I should have.
放心吧 我正在召集你的组员
Don't worry, I'm assembling your team now.
这是我的葬礼 我要自己挑组员
It's my funeral. My pick of the team.
随你高兴
Any way you want it.
不是很漂亮 对吧？
They aren't much to look at, are they?
我们打造它们 不是做漂亮的事
Well, we didn't build them to do pretty things.
医生
Hey, doc.
- 他几时信教的？- 我不会说是信教
- When did he get the religion? - I wouldn't call it religion per se.
- 是精神上的 - 那不一样
- He's spiritual. - That's different.
两个月前 我半夜接到电话
Yeah, two months ago, I received a call in the middle of the night.
我一个礼拜没见到他了
I hadn't seen him for a week.
他说他去了沙漠 接受测试
He told me he'd been in the desert and that he'd been tested.
他变得不一样了
He wasn't himself.
继续说
Go on.
每个人 就算是圣人
Well, every man, even great men…
在他们疲累害怕的时候 都会心存疑虑
…experience moments of doubt when they're tired and afraid.
害怕什么？
Afraid of what?
他说这场战争永远不会结束
He told me that this was a war that would never end.
如果我们这样下去
That if we stay this course…
虫族将来一定会 摧毁人类
…the Bugs will and must destroy the human race.
所以他就疯了
So he's lost his nut.
非常好 十分满分
Extraordinary, 10 out of 10.
他病情复发 我给他开镇静剂
He had an episode. I gave him a sedative.
隔天他叫我不用担心 他和上帝谈过了
The next day he told me not to worry, that he'd talked to God.
如果我说我和上帝对话 你会不准我驾驶吗？
Doc, if I told you I was talking to God, would you clear me for flight?
我…
I…
空军指挥官是否不适合指挥？
Is the SM unfit for command?
我觉得这段对话 很不舒服 舰长
I find this a very uncomfortable conversation, captain.
如果我要接手指挥 就会需要你的协助
If I need to assume command, I'm gonna need your help…
因为其它人不会懂的
…because the others won't understand.
我们两个都会被处死
We could both hang.
你是效忠空军指挥官还是对联邦？
Is your loyalty to the SM or the Federation?
别怪厨师 各位
Don't blame the cook, folks.
空军指挥官先吃
The SM goes first.
只有水而已 布尔 你吃我的
Just water. Bull, you have mine.
你确定吗 长官？
Are you sure, sir?
我相信我们会需要你的体力
Well, I'm sure we'll need your strength.
谢谢长官
Thank you, sir.
如果您不介意 我们饭前可以祷告吗？
If you don't mind, can we maybe say a prayer before we eat?
当然可以
Of course.
威斯医生？
Dr. Wiggs?
贝克舰长 你呢？
Captain Beck, how about you?
我去查看边界 长官
I'll be checking the perimeter, sir.
感谢主赐给我们这顿饭
We thank thee, Lord, for the meal we're about to receive.
请保佑我们 守护我们
Please bless us and keep us.
保护我们避开邪恶 引领我们
Protect us from all evil and guide us…
让我们知道走向你的路
…that we may know the way to you.
阿门
Amen.
- 阿门 - 阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
可以请教您 一个问题吗 长官？
Can I ask you a question, sir?
当然可以 布尔
Of course, Bull.
他们会来找我们吧？
They are gonna come looking for us, won't they, sir?
因为有你在
Because of you.
我们的任务是最重要的 布尔
We are on a mission of the greatest importance, Bull.
即使我们现在 并不清楚目的何在
Even if we do not now understand our purpose.
是的 长官 但我们会获救的
Yes, sir. But we are gonna be rescued.
这点你很清楚吧？
I mean, you do know that, don't you?
因为你是通灵战士
Because you're psychic.
我知道周围人的感受 有时也能和他们对话
I know how people around me feel, and sometimes I can speak to them…
但没人能预测未来 布尔
…but no one can predict the future, Bull.
我也有一个问题
I have a question for you.
要请教你们大家
For all of you.
你们有信仰吗？
Do you have faith?
我有
I believe.
我知道你有 荷莉 你的信仰明确且虔诚
I know you do, Holly. Your faith is clear and serene.
我也想要有 长官
I wanna believe too, sir.
是真的
I really do.
总是个开始 布尔
Well, that's the start of it, Bull.
威斯医生 你呢？
Dr. Wiggs, how about you?
我相信你 长官
I believe in you, sir.
小心点 威斯医生
Well, careful now, Dr. Wiggs.
因为我只是一介凡人
See, I'm only a man.
地震
Earthquake.
敌人来袭！
Incoming!
救我！布尔！
Help me! Bull!
- 金格 - 撑住
- Jingo, Jingo. - Hold on.
撑住 金格
Hold on, Jingo.
加油 加油
Come on, come on!
天啊
Jesus.
威斯呢？
Where's Wiggs?
威斯医生？
Dr. Wiggs?
威斯？
Wiggs?
医生？
Doc?
威斯？
Wiggs?
医生？
Doc?
很高兴又见到你们 大兵
Good to see you again, troopers.
现在你们都参与了 一项机密任务
You are now all part of a classified mission.
说出去你就会被处死 明白吗？
Talk about it and they will hang you. Get me?
明白 长官
We get you, sir.
请问掠夺者计划 究竟是什么 长官？
What exactly is the Marauder program, sir?
- 我目前不便透露 - 这项任务会送死吗 长官？
- I'm not currently at liberty to say. - Sir, is the mission survivable, sir?
我们会知道的 大兵
We'll find out, trooper.
你知道我怎么想吗 长官？
You know what I think, sir?
- 你怎么想 少尉？- 今天是慷慨赴义的好日子
- What's that, sergeant? - I think it's a good day to die, sir.
非常好 很高兴你这么想
Outstanding. Glad you feel that way.
因为今天我们要前往 虫族隔离区
Because today, we're headed out for the Arachnid Quarantine Zone.
- 准备出发 大兵 - 遵命 长官
- Saddle up, troopers. - Sir, yes, sir.
豪泽呼叫兰柏
Hauzer for Lamb.
抱歉 将军 兰柏少尉被调职了
I'm sorry, general, Lieutenant Lamb's been transferred.
调去哪里？
Where?
抱歉 长官 我不能告诉你
I'm sorry, sir, I can't tell you that.
（搜寻中）
（状态：等待处死 | 罪名：煽动罪）
（签署人：艾诺萝菲德上将）
什么？
What?
- 狄克斯 请进 - 你要吊死兰柏？
- Dix, come in. - You are going to hang Lamb?
红发小女孩 眼神悲伤 有张大嘴巴？
Little redhead, sad eyes, big mouth?
为什么？
Why?
那是叛徒的下场 狄克斯
That is what happens to traitors, Dix.
看来你很了解叛徒 上将
Seems like you know all about traitors, admiral.
也许我现在 正看着一个叛徒呢
Maybe I'm looking at one right now.
你也要把我吊死？
So you're gonna hang me too?
这种事这阵子很多
Well, a lot of that going around these days.
如果被议会发现 你压制空军指挥官的求救讯号
What happens to you when the council finds out…
你会有什么下场呢？
…you suppressed the sky marshal's rescue call?
谁会告诉他们这种事？
And exactly who would tell them such a thing?
你把OM一号星球的 座标告诉我然后辞职
You give me the coordinates for Planet OM-1, resign…
我就不会说出去
…and I keep my mouth shut.
抱歉 狄克斯
I'm sorry, Dix.
但欧马艾诺克很快就会身亡
But very shortly, Omar Anoke will be dead…
被尊为联邦的英雄
…and honored as a hero of the Federation…
而我会成为下一任空军指挥官
…and I will be the next sky marshal.
除非你先干掉我
Over my dead body.
那是你最后的要求吗 将军？
That your last request, general?
（新闻快报）
联邦议员今日齐聚一堂
Federal Council members were called together today…
听取空军指挥官艾诺克例行周报
…by Sky Marshal Anoke for his weekly report.
你好吗？很高兴见到你
How are you doing, sir? Good to see you.
然后…悲剧发生
Then… disaster.
戈尼夫和平联盟成员 携带炸弹引爆
A bomb carried by a member of the Goniff Peace Coalition explodes.
失踪名单包括
Among the missing:
空军指挥官艾诺克及其忠贞的助手 狄克斯豪泽将军
Sky Marshal Anoke and his loyal aide, General Dix Hauzer.
今天 我们每一个人
Today, each and every one of us…
都受到了攻击 而攻击的人
…has been attacked by a man…
宣称不惜一切代价 要求和平
…who would demand peace at all costs.
他自称是公民
A man who calls himself a citizen.
他其实比虫族还不如
A man who is no better than a Bug.
- 再多打一天… - 那个人就是艾莫戈尼夫
- One more day of fighting… - That man is Elmo Goniff…
自称和平主义者 却成了恐怖份子
…self-proclaimed pacifist turned terrorist.
今天 他与戈尼夫和平联盟 的其它成员
And today, he and other members of the Goniff Peace Coalition…
都因为与议会爆炸案有关 而遭到通缉
…are wanted in connection with the council bombing.
小市民 你可以帮忙
And, hey, citizen, you can help.
- 去认识你的邻居 - 把那鬼东西拿开
- Know your neighbors? - Turn that f***ing thing off.
- 再看一眼 公民 - 你说我吗？
- Take another look, citizen. - Who, me?
你可能就住在 一大笔赏金的隔壁
You could be living next door to a big, fat reward.
你看到什么就说出来
If you see something, say something.
想知道更多吗？
Would you like to know more?
这里是虫族隔离区
We're in the Arachnid Quarantine Zone.
知道什么意思吗？这是虫族的星球
Do you know what that means? This is a Bug planet.
它们随时会来抓我们 对吧？
They could come for us at any time, right?
- 天上地下谁晓得 - 省省吧 金格
- Upstairs, downstairs, you can't tell. - Save your breath, Jingo.
但它们搞不好就在脚下 你又不知道
Yeah, but they could be under our feet right now. You can't tell.
- 你不知道吧？- 听我说好吗？
- You don't know, right? - Listen to me, okay?
我会告诉你什么时候跑
I'll tell you when to run.
不 你不会告诉我什么时候跑 因为我是厨师 懂吗？
No, you can't tell me when to run, because I'm a cook, okay?
我接受快速点餐 我不是…
I take short orders, I'm not a…
你给我振作一点
Get your shit wired.
你这个恶婆娘
You're a bitch.
我们走
Let's move.
- 你在浪费水 金格 - 我恨你
- You're wasting water, Jingo. - I hate you.
- 天哪 - 没事的 荷莉
- Oh, God. - It's okay, Holly.
够了 我要离开这里
Oh, that's it, I'm out of here.
留在原地 金格 这是命令
Hold your ground, Jingo. That's an order.
贝克舰长 我们需要谈一谈
Captain Beck, we need to talk.
真是天杀的
We're fucked.
那正是我一直在说的
That's exactly what I've been saying.
你不该那样说 那是亵渎神明的
You shouldn't talk like that. That's blasphemy.
你是个该死的空服员 少废话
You're a goddamn flight attendant, so stow it.
我们根本不该离开海滩
We never should have left the goddamn beach.
真是大错特错
This is all a big mistake.
现在我们有战士
Now we got warriors…
该死的地震 还失去了医生
…fucking earthquakes, and we even lost the doc.
你们忘了吗？这都是你的错
Did you forget that? And it's your fault.
如果我们留在海滩
You know, if we'd stayed at the beach…
就能躺在沙滩上
…then we could just be lying in the sand.
如果虫族出现 我们就跳进海里
And if the Bugs did show up, well, then we just jump in the water.
虫族不会游泳 对吧？它们会吗？
I mean, Bugs don't swim, right? Do they?
- 金格 你背后 - 金格 小心背后
- Jingo, behind you. - Jingo, watch your back.
是啊 很好笑
Yeah. Very funny.
知道吗？去你们的 我要回去海滩
You know what? Screw you guys. I'm going back to the beach.
- 金格 - 金格
- Jingo. - Jingo.
金格 不要
Jingo, don't.
站住 金格
Hold on, Jingo.
可恶
Damn it.
他妈的
Fucker.
它走掉了
It's moving off.
停火 省省子弹
Hold your fire. Save the ammo.
- 金格 马上出来 - 才不要
- Jingo, get out of there, now. - No way.
我们应该进去陪他 我们走
We ought to get in there with him. Let's go.
队长 那不是石头 快离开那里
Chief, those aren't rocks. Get out of there now.
- 走吧 荷莉 长官 - 不 朋友
- Come on, Holly, let's go. Sir, let's go. - No, my friends.
他是属於上帝的
He belongs to God.
你在说什么啊？
What are you talking about?
不
No.
No, no.
不
No.
现在你的上帝在哪里？
And where's your God now?
我们走
Let's move.
就算你不信 舰长 他也有在听
Even though you don't believe it, captain, he is listening.
- 我们很快就会得救 - 你真的相信吗 长官？
- And soon, we will be delivered. - Do you really believe that, sir?
是的 荷莉
Yes, Holly.
我相信
I do.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
因为他现在就在跟我对话 贝克舰长
Because he talks to me even now, Captain Beck.
他现在就在跟我对话
He talks to me even now.
大家听好 你们操作的硬碟
All right, listen up. The hardware you'll be operating…
会和你们的神经系统 直接连结
…interfaces directly with your nervous system.
真厉害 长官
That's outstanding, sir.
请脱掉衣服
Please remove your clothing.
如果不买农场 你会做什么？
What are you gonna do if you don't buy the farm?
我想退休 他们说不定会让我们回家
I'm thinking R and R. They might even let us go home.
家？那是什么？
Home? What's that?
平静安详和家人 记得吗？
Peace and quiet, family. Remember?
对 事情结束后 我要的就是那些
Yeah, that's all I want when this is done.
我等不及重新来过了
Yeah, I just can't wait for it to be over and start living again.
没人跟你说过吗 中士？
Hasn't anybody told you, sergeants?
死是机动步兵团 唯一的归宿
Mobile Infantry is only good for dying.
他们必须想出更大的武器
They need to come up with a bigger weapon…
才能解决这件事 我们才能回家
…so they can finish this thing and we can go home.
对 虫虫再见
Yeah. Bye-bye, Bugs.
战争结束你要做什么 长官？
What will you do when the war is over, sir?
你们在说什么？这场战争永远不会结束
What are you people talking about? This war is never gonna end.
二号请就位
Take your place, number two.
难怪他妈妈叫他鼻涕虫
I guess that's why his mama called him Slug.
准备进行全光谱生物扫描
Prepare for full-spectrum bioscan.
DDQ五乘五
DDQ, five-by-five.
开始进行珈玛扫描
Commencing Gamma Jetta Bonza.
（神经机械介面完成）
（掠夺者小组就绪）
（艾拉莫湾地下研究机构）
你有参与艾诺克 审问首脑吗 将军？
Did you participate in Anoke's interrogation of the Brain, general?
没有
No.
所以你不知道副作用？
So you don't know about the side effects?
什么副作用？
What side effects?
看来只要是和那只虫 相处太久的人
It seems anybody who spends too much time around that Bug…
都会出现幻觉 包括生理与心理上
…suffers deleterious effects, both physical and psychological.
- 空军指挥官没有 - 看来是如此
- Not the sky marshal. - So it seemed.
事实上我们不完全知道 首脑的本事
Truth is, we didn't fully understand the Brain's capabilities.
- 长官好 - 欢迎来到第六区 将军
- Sir. - Welcome to Area 6, admiral.
- 只准必要人士进入 - 遵命 长官
- Necessary personnel only. - Yes, sir.
所有未经许可的人士 请立刻离开第六区
All unauthorized personnel, exit Area 6 immediately.
将军 你对空军指挥官的了解 究竟有多少？
So, general, how well did you really know the sky marshal?
我每天和他共事
I worked with him every day.
所以你知道他有了信仰
So you knew he got religion.
- 你们在说什么？- 将军
- What are you talking about? - General.
我想有个东西你该看一看
There's something I think you should see.
打开艾诺克档案
Run the Anoke file.
这是艾诺克和首脑虫的 监视录影划片
This is surveillance footage of Anoke with the Brain Bug.
我们最近才发现的
We just recently discovered it.
他在做心灵接触 他们在沟通
He's psychically connected with it. They communicate.
我明白
I understand.
我来此做你的仆人 毕罕科托
And I come here as your servant, Behemecoytal.
- 那玩意儿有名字？- 对 但不是这只虫
- That thing has a name? - Yeah. But that's not this Bug.
毕罕科托很可能 是我们没见过的某只虫
Behemecoytal is likely some Bug we've never encountered before.
源自OM一号星球的 高等虫族智慧生物
A superior arachnid intelligence originating on the planet OM-1.
OM一号？
OM-1?
我们相信这个首脑 是自愿被捕的
We believe this Brain allowed itself to be captured.
提供来自联邦核心的情报
To provide intelligence from the heart of the Federation.
艾诺克利用首脑 和这个毕罕科托连系
And Anoke used the Brain to commune with this Behemecoytal.
他视那只虫为上帝
A Bug he regards as God.
是的 罗库山会打败仗 以证实我的信仰
Yes, Roku San will fall as proof of my faith.
然后我们就能来谈 和平的条件
Then we can discuss the terms of peace.
艾诺克要为罗库山负责？
Anoke's responsible for Roku San?
他有关闭围栏的密码
He had the codes to shut down the fences.
他和虫子签下协议 让罗库山无力抵抗
He made a pact with the Bug to render Roku San defenseless.
根据他的转变
And in light of his conversion…
他成了虫族的资产 对我们则大不利
…he's become an asset to the Bugs and a tremendous liability for us.
那么 艾诺克在OM一号做什么呢
So, the real question is, what's Anoke doing in OM-1?
- 交朋友？- 你不能和一直虫子交朋友
- Making friends? - You can't be friends with a Bug.
所以我们要解决这一只
That's why we're gonna put this one down…
拆了它 查出它知道什么
…take it apart, and find out what it knows.
关闭围墙
Close the containment.
上将 你没事吧？
Admiral, you okay?
没事
Yeah.
你看看他
Look at him.
银河系最有权力的人 找到了上帝
The most powerful man in the galaxy finds God…
结果他怎么做？
…and what does he do?
照对方说的去做
Exactly what he's told.
他是虫子
He's a Bug.
不会想 不会抗议 不会造反
Doesn't think, doesn't protest, doesn't rebel.
这种态度才能打蠃战争
That's the kind of attitude that wins wars.
你知道吗 狄克斯
You know, Dix…
我想这些虫子在算计什么
…I think these Bugs are onto something.
这搞不好是它们 最厉害的武器
This could just be the greatest weapon of them all.
他是怎么办到的？
How does he do it?
那是信仰 布尔 那样才叫男人
That's faith, Bull. That's what it does for a man.
省省吧
Give it a break.
信仰比Q弹更厉害
Faith is more powerful than a Q-bomb.
没有信仰 你什么都不是
Without it, you're nobody.
所以我不要 再听你的话了 舰长
That's why I'm not listening to you anymore, captain.
荷莉 如果我们能逃出去 我在想…
Holly, if we ever get out of this, I was wondering if…
也许…
Well…
怎样 布尔？
What is it, Bull?
你愿意嫁给 我这种大老粗吗？
Would you ever marry an old monkey wrench like me?
只要是在教堂就行 布尔
Only in a church, Bull.
你是说真的？
You mean it?
你接受上帝 就能娶到我
You take God and you can take me.
我们的目的地
What we've come for.
就在这里
It's here.
我从未怀疑过 长官
I never doubted it for a second, sir.
就算我以前不信 现在也信了
If I didn't believe before, I do now.
- 亲爱的 一切会没事的 - 你会如愿的 比尔
- Honey, everything's gonna be okay. - All will be well, Bull.
你会知道上帝的名
And you will know the name of God.
真正的上帝
The one true God.
毕罕科托
Behemecoytal.
首脑之脑
Brain of Brains.
- 毕罕什么？- 毕罕科托
- Beheme-what? - Behemecoytal.
他在这里 他无所不在
He's here. He's everywhere.
来吧 我们去休息 等待他的到来
Come, and let us rest and wait for his coming.
人家说上帝有好多名字 但我从没听过这一个
They say God has many names, but I've never heard that one before.
亲爱的 他是飞官 他懂的比我们多
Well, honey, he's the sky marshal. He knows a lot more than we do.
他说的是虫子
He's talking about a Bug.
他认为上帝是虫？
He thinks God is a Bug?
他有信仰 虫族的信仰
He's got religion. Their religion.
- 虫族的信仰？- 太扯了
- Bug religion? - That's crazy.
那是亵渎神明的
That's blasphemy.
现在怎么办？
What do we do now?
也许我们该杀了他
Maybe we should kill him.
为什么？因为他疯了？还是因为他像你一样信神？
Why, because he's crazy? Or he believes in God like you?
他信错神了
It's the wrong God.
- 你去守门 - 我不是步兵
- Guard the door. - I'm no trooper.
你好 公民
Greetings, citizen.
借过一下 长官
Excuse me, sir.
- 出了什么错？- 漏气
- What went wrong? - An air leak.
船身自行着地的
The ship landed itself.
他们进入大气层前就死了
They were dead before they hit the atmosphere.
席拉麦克号呼叫救援舰
Sierra Mike Uniform to Fleet Rescue.
听到请回答
Come in, Fleet.
席拉麦克号呼叫救援舰 听到请回答
Sierra Mike Uniform to Fleet Rescue. Come in, Fleet.
如果我能解决氧气问题 就能飞上轨道
We could make orbit if I can solve the O2 problem.
搞定它 队长
Solve it, chief.
席拉麦克号呼叫救援舰
Sierra Mike Uniform to Fleet Rescue.
听到请回答
Come in.
席拉麦克号 这里是救援舰 请说
Sierra Mike Uniform, this is Fleet Rescue, over.
请求优先接回 OM一号星球
We are requesting priority pickup on Planet Oscar Mike-One…
包括飞官和另外三名生还者
…for SM and three additional survivors.
荷莉 不要动
Holly, don't move.
我们走 宝贝
Let's go, baby.
快走 宝贝
Go, baby.
布尔
Bull.
不！
No!
它们到处都是
It's all around.
- 是毕罕科托 - 不 是地狱
- It's Behemecoytal. - No, it's hell.
- 来吧 荷莉 - 这是地狱！
- Come on, Holly. - We're in hell!
把门关上 荷莉
Clear the door, Holly.
我们或许无法上轨道
We may not be able to make orbit.
- 但我们肯定能离开这里 - 我们必须留下 舰长
- But we can sure get out of here. - We must remain here, captain.
不 长官 我们要离开这里
No, sir, we are off this rock.
伟大的主啊
Oh, great one. Lord.
这一天终於到来 我就站在你面前
The day has arrived that I stand before you.
让我们开始交流吧
Let our communion begin.
是的
Yes.
是时候交谈了
It's time to talk.
金格 是你吗？
Jingo, is that you?
他替我们发言 我们得以用人类语言交谈
This one speaks for us that we may talk to you as a man.
你们和自己人对话 应该会比较自在
That you may be comfortable among your own kind.
你们信任的顾问与仆人
Among your trusted advisors and servants…
变成了我们的信徒
…whom we have made believers.
感谢主
Thank you, Lord.
你是如此在乎我
That you care for me so much…
让我充满爱与喜乐 还有自信
…fills me with love and joy and confidence…
我们可以也将会 建立全新的认识
…that we can and will create a great new understanding.
你将成为我们的一员
You will be one with us.
这样我就会了解你
So that I may come to know you.
你会了解 我们知道的东西
You will know what we know.
你也会了解我 并且透过我
And that you will come to know me, and through me…
了解全人类
…all of humankind.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我是来跟比我们优越的种族 做和平协商
I am here to negotiate peace with a being superior to us.
- 姑息它们吗？- 不 贝克舰长
- What, appeasement? - No, Captain Beck.
是谈人类的存活 我们都会得救
The survival of the human race. We will all be saved.
请见谅 我的人要学的还很多
Forgive me. My people have much to learn.
- 他们害怕又… - 跟你以前一样 艾诺克
- They are fearful and… - As were you once, Anoke.
我曾经怯懦
I was weak.
你要求罗库山 那么多条生命 我怀疑过
When you asked for the lives of so many at Roku San, I doubted.
但现在我明白 伟大的成就…
But now I understand that great achievement…
都需要大量的牺牲
…requires great sacrifice.
你把罗库山交给它们
You gave them Roku San.
叛徒
Traitor.
透过那个女人 你会找到圣域
Within that woman you will find Sanctuary.
我把解除冲突的关键 献给你
I have given you the key that will end this conflict once and for all…
让你的律法来统治 让乐园降临…
…so that your law may rule and paradise follow…
你是骗子 坏人
You're a liar. Seducer.
奉主之名
He of a thousand names.
伟大的主啊
Oh, great one, Lord…
请你带走这两个女人 杀了她们吧？
…would you please take these women from me and kill them?
你为何希望这么做？
And why do you wish this?
我走过这趟伟大的旅程
I have made this great journey.
我进化了
I have evolved.
我牺牲了一切
I have sacrificed all…
这样我才能 与你创造大和平
…so that I may create with you a great peace.
她们却想搞砸
And they're fucking it up.
我们也寻求和平 只是方法不同
We too seek peace, but by different means.
我们寻求知识
We seek knowledge.
知识是理解…
Knowledge is the key to understanding…
与沟通的关键
…and to communication.
唯有如此 我等一族…
And only by this way can our species…
才会与众不同 和谐共处 互荣…
…so different, live together in harmony and mutual resp…
你会成为我们的一员
You will become one with us…
提供必要的知识
…and provide the knowledge necessary…
平定人类一族
…to pacify the human species.
主啊 好的
Oh, Lord. Yes.
你们的计划 你们的军队配置
Your plans, the disposition of your armies…
和舰队配置
…your fleet.
是的 我的就是你的
Yes, what's mine is yours.
带我走 伟大的主
Take me unto you, oh, great one.
是的
Yes.
跟我一起祷告 萝拉
Pray with me, Lola.
什么？
What?
主啊 请听我的祷告 带我们离开这邪恶之地
Lord, please hear my prayer. Deliver us from this evil place.
- 快 萝拉 跟我一起祷告 - 这有什么差别呢
- Come on, Lola, pray with me. - It doesn't make any difference.
主啊 派给我们 一个天使军队
Lord, send us an army of angels.
让他们配备 你的火与你的剑
And arm them with your fire and your sword…
让他们歼灭 我们周围的邪恶
…that they might smite the evil around us.
怎么了 萝拉？
What is it, Lola?
萝拉 怎么了？
Lola, what is it?
来吧 萝拉 难道你不想活吗？
Come on, Lola, don't you wanna live?
我想活下去
Yes, I wanna live.
当你希望尽失 上帝就是你仅有的了
Well, when you're all out of hope, God is all you get.
说吧
Now, say it.
- 我们的天父 - 我们的天父
- Our father. - Our father.
- 在天上的父 - 在天上的父
- Who art in heaven. - Who art in heaven.
愿世人皆颂圣名
Hallowed be they name.
- 愿您的国降临 - 愿您的国降临
- Thy kingdom come. - Thy kingdom come.
- 愿您的旨意 - 愿您的旨意
- Thy will be done. - Thy will be done.
- 行在地上如同行在天上 - 行在地上如同行在天上
- On Earth as it is in heaven. - On Earth as it is in heaven.
大兵 歼灭这个虫穴 到处都是亚契
All right, troopers, let's fix this hive. Archies everywhere.
免我们的债 如同我们免了人的债
As we forgive those who trespass against us.
- 寻找生还者 - 不叫我们预见试探
- Searching for survivors. - And lead us not into temptation.
- 找到了 - 救我们脱离邪恶
- Got them. - And deliver us from evil.
前进吧
Let's move in.
接近中
Rolling in.
看到了
We got visual.
瞄准
Hold your fire.
等我的指令
Wait for my command.
- 看到了 接触敌人 - 等待指令
- We got visual, we got contact. - Wait for it.
就绪 等待指令
Ready. Wait for it.
接触敌人
We got contact.
我要拨枪了
I'm moving in for guns.
保持冷静
Keep your cool.
别轻举妄动 大兵
Hold that line, trooper.
再说一次 萝拉 再说一次
Say it again, Lola. Say it again.
- 我们在天上的父 - 在天上的父
- Our father who art in heaven. - Who art in heaven.
- 愿世人皆颂圣名 - 愿世人皆颂圣名
- Hallowed by thy name. - Hallowed by thy name.
开火
Fire in the hole.
- 行在地上如同行在天上 - 行在地上如同行在天上
- On Earth as it is in heaven. - On Earth as it is in heaven.
开始攻击
Open up.
用尽所有武器
Everything you got.
听我倒数开始扫射
Initiate wide dispersal on my mark.
- 三 二… - 免我们的债
- Three, two… - And forgive us our trespasses.
开火！
Fire!
杀光它们 一个不留
Weed them out. Nothing lives.
杀了它们
Get some, get some, get some.
亚契
Archie.
两个目标
Dual target.
- 阿门 - 阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
好 宰了它们
All right, cook them.
走吧 萝拉 我们回家了
Come on, Lola, let's go home.
你在那儿杀了一堆虫 强尼
You killed a lot of Bugs down there, John.
- 可惜大虫跑了 - 它是大虫嘛
- Too bad the big one got away. - Well, it's a big Bug.
我们的人搞不清楚 虫子在哪终结 星球从哪开始
Our guys can't tell where the Bug ends and the planet begins.
很难想像有什么 能活着熬过去
Hard to imagine anything could live through all that.
- 我办到啦 - 你很难死嘛
- I did. - You're hard to kill.
虫子好大
The Bug is big.
我们锁定它了
We have lock.
贝克舰长
Captain Beck.
久仰大名
I've heard a lot about you.
我希望你来指挥我的旗舰
I'm hoping you'll take command of my flagship.
不过你要先休息一下
But when you've had a little time off.
好的 长官
Yes, ma'am.
恭喜你 瑞哥上校 掠夺者大成功
Congratulations, Colonel Rico. Marauder is a big success.
- 谢谢长官 - 谢谢狄克斯吧
- Thank you, ma'am. - Oh, thank Dix.
我的新副手 很少接受人家的拒绝
My new number two doesn't always take no for an answer.
我不确定是否应该 寓公事于娱乐
I wasn't sure we should mix business with pleasure.
- 准备配置Q弹了吗？- 就等您一声令下
- Are we ready to deploy the Q-bomb? - On your command.
很好 我们去炸星球吧
All right, people. Let's go crack a planet.
他们要上你升将军 强尼
So they wanna make you a general, John.
让你负责整个掠夺者计划
Put you in charge of the whole Marauder program.
我只会做一件事 狄克斯
I'm only good for one thing, Dix.
给我一个小队 让我打仗
Give me a squad and let me fight.
至少考虑一下嘛
At least think about it.
也许你们两个想独处
Maybe you two wanna be alone.
我们回程见
I'll see you on the bounce.
倒数计时 发射
Alpha Gamma Bonza. Now.
我想问你
I wanted to ask you…
你愿不愿意…
Would you?
我愿意
I will.
真的？
Really?
- 太好了 - 但你得知道一件事
- That's wonderful. - But you need to know one thing.
什么事？
Yeah?
我在底下发生了一件事
Something happened to me down there and…
三十秒后撞击
Thirty seconds to impact.
- 是我无法解释的事 - 什么？
- Something that I can't explain. - What?
如果你要娶我 就得在教堂举行
But if you wanna marry me, we have to do it in a church.
- 什么？- 二十秒后撞击
- What? - Twenty seconds to impact.
我信教了 狄克斯 信的很深
I got religion, Dix. I got it bad.
十秒
Ten seconds.
没有人是完美的
Well, nobody's perfect.
五 四 三 二 一
Five, four, three, two, one.
引爆成功
We have detonation.
没错 他离开了 但他留下了一首歌
Sure, he's gone, but he left us with a song.
（现在就捐款 公民！）
（你也能哀悼！）
勇气
Courage.
负责
Duty.
荣誉
Honor.
数百万人哀悼 空军指挥官欧·艾诺克的死
Millions mourn the passing of Sky Marshal Omar Anoke.
他是战士 哲学家 是联邦的英雄
Warrior, philosopher, a hero of the Federation.
（收录畅销单曲 《慷慨赴义就在今天》）
（《别再虫我》与《性感灵媒》）
联邦各地专家都同意
Across the Federation, federal experts agree that, A…
一 上帝是存在的 二 他站在我们这边
…God exists after all, B, he's on our side…
三 他要我们蠃
…and, C, he wants us to win.
还有更好的消息 众信徒
And there's even more good news, believers.
因为这是官方消息 上帝回来了
Because it's official. God's back.
他也是个公民
And he's a citizen too.
屈于联邦各地人气攀升
Bowing to a rise in popularity all across the Federation…
菲德空军指挥官宣布 宗教是可以接受的
…Sky Marshal Phid declares that while religion is acceptable…
但和平则不是
…peace is not.
其它相关消息 和平恐怖份子艾莫戈尼夫
In related news, peace terrorist Elmo Goniff…
及其51名密友 今早被处以绞刑
…and 51 of his closest friends were hung this morning…
许多人相信 这是自21世纪以来
…in what many believe to be the all-time record for executions…
单日处决人数的最高纪录
…in a single day since the 21 st century.
但他们无法让你沉默
But they can't silence you.
去他的联邦 去你的！你们夺不走我的声音！
F*** the Federation and f*** all of you! You will not take my voice!
你们夺不走我！你们夺不走我们的权力！
You will not take me! You will not take away our power!
去你的！去你的！
F*** you all! F*** you! F*** you all!
去他的联邦！
F*** the Federation!
战争英雄休假结婚去了
War heroes take time out to tie the knot.
（联邦名人敲响礼钟）
回去工作吧 大兵
Get back to work, troopers.
没人告诉你们吗？又有战争了
Didn't anyone tell you? There's a war on.
加入军队尽一份力量
So join up, do your part.
眼前还有冗长的战争 我们需要你
There's a long war ahead, and we need you.
你准备好当掠夺者了吗？
Are you ready for Marauder?
加入机动步兵团
Join the Mobile Infantry…
加入机动步兵团看你是不是当公民的料
…and see if you've got what it takes to be a citizen.
我们回程见了 大兵
See you on the bounce, trooper.
服役就能获得公民权
Service guarantees citizenship.